Othman Shareef

othmanosx@gmail.com | https://othman.itechnopro.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/othmanosx

About me:

I'm a frontend web developer with a demonstrated history of working in the software engineering industry for over 6 years. I love working on projects, converting ideas and UI's to functional web applications, and enjoy doing the front-end part where I use my skills in user interface design. I create websites and web apps using javascript, typescript, and their frameworks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2021 - CURRENT

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER - GATEWAY ICT

- Built MyTVAds (Advertising Platform) from zero to live utilizing best practices and responsive design with a mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Built Fastlink eSIM admin dashboard to generate and manage eSIM contracts.
- Launched and maintained the MyTV+ streaming service app on Hisense Smart TVs with thousands of movies and TV shows.
- Worked remotely and directly in collaboration with UX/UI designers and backend developers, converting designs into real-world projects and implementing RESTful APIs.
- Did code reviews, mentored junior developers, and lead the frontend team.
- Released updates for live projects fixing bugs and memory leaks, adding new features and big performance improvements.
- Implemented websites, web applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment using the latest technologies like React, ES6 & ES7 JavaScript, Typescript, CSS & HTML, and Material UI.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

12/2014 - CURRENT

WEB DEVELOPER - ITECH

- Website owner, manager, and organizer.
- Professional Blogger, Front-end web developer, Copywriter, Software reviewer, articles, and report writer with 6+ years of experience.
- Sponsored and collaborated with many big software companies including Tenorshare, iMobie, GearBest,
 Digiarty, and many others.

2014 - 2021

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Built websites and web apps for clients.
- English-Arabic translator. Converted websites and software user interfaces from English to Arabic.
- · Graphic Designer (Photoshop and Illustrator). / Data management using Excel (Microsoft Office suite).
- Sponsored and collaborated with the company and did reviews for new products and software.

PROJECTS

MyTVAds (MyTV+ Advertising Platform)

An enterprise-grade advertisement platform for businesses to create and manage their own advertisement campaigns. Technologies: React JS, JavaScript, Material UI, Redux.

Live Link: https://mytvadz.com/

Appollow

A PWA website and mobile app to help people create accounts to share and find great, special and discounted apps and games. Technologies: Next JS, TypeScript, Nodejs, MongoDB, PWA, Bootstrap, Firebase, Redux.

Live Link: https://www.appollow.net/
Teaser: https://appollow-teaser.vercel.app/

GraphQL Web 3 App

Technologies: React, Nextjs, GraphQL, Apollo client, Web 3, Chakra UI, BigNumberjs, Framer-Motion Github repo: https://github.com/Othmanosx/hal-web3-graphql

Live: https://hal-othman.vercel.app/

Fullstack E-commerce POC

Technologies: TypeScript, React, Nextjs, Firebase, SASS,

Github repo: https://github.com/Othmanosx/bejamas-ecommerce-poc

Live: https://bejamas-othman.vercel.app/

FindYours

The idea of the project is to help people find their missing stuff, will let people post the things they lost or found, and every post will contain the info a user may need to contact the person.

Technologies: React JS, Material UI CSS Framework, Firebase, Redux, Prettier, ESlint.

Live Demo: https://findyours.netlify.app/

Weather app

Provide weather forecasts over a 6-day period updated each day for more than 2000 cities.

Technologies: React JS, HTML, CSS

Live Demo: https://weather-app-othman.netlify.app/

Hangman Game

Hangman is a word guessing game that I developed using ReactJS in which the user guesses the word generated randomly by the game from an API. Live Demo: https://hangman-sand-team.netlify.app/

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT - Flatiron School - Re:Coded

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPMENT - Kodluyoruz

POWER SKILLS: BUSINESS COMMUNICATION, AGILE, SCRUM, TEAM WORK, TIME MANAGEMENT - Re:Coded

BACHELOR IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING - University of Mosul

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): ARABIC

Other language(s):

ENGLISH | TURKISH

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

React js | Git (GitHub) | Agile (Scrum & Kanban) | Context API | Redux | CI / CD | MUI (Material UI) |
Firebase | HTML | CSS | Javascript | Typescript | SASS | Bootstrap | SEO | Nextjs | Responsive Web
Design | GraphQL | MongoDB | Nodejs | NoSQL | PWA | RESTful APIs | UI/UX | Photoshop | Illustrator